mpsocial.com 2019-02-14

# Privacy Policy - MP Social

This notice describes how [MpSocial](https://mpsocial.com/), collects and uses data about you.

**Jump to:**

  * What information do we collect?
  * What do we use your information for?
  * How do we protect your information?
  * What is your data retention policy?
  * Do we use cookies?
  * Do we disclose any information to outside parties?
  * Third party links
  * Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance
  * Online Privacy Policy Only
  * Does MpSocial comply with the EU General Data Protection Regulation?
  * Where can I access data about me?
  * How can I change or erase data about me?
  * Does MpSocial make automated decisions based on data about me?
  * Does MpSocial share data about me with others?
  * How can I contact MpSocial about privacy?
  * What if this privacy notice changes?
  * Your Consent
  * Changes to our Privacy Policy

* * *

## What information do we collect?

We collect information from you when you register on our site and gather data when you participate in the forum by reading, writing, and evaluating the content shared here.

When registering on our site, you may be asked to enter your name and e-mail address. You may, however, visit our site without registering. Your e-mail address will be verified by an email containing a unique link. If that link is visited, we know that you control the e-mail address.

When registered and posting, we record the IP address that the post originated from. We also may retain server logs which include the IP address of every request to our server.

## What do we use your information for?

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To personalize your experience — your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs.
  * To improve our site — we continually strive to improve our site offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you.
  * To improve customer service — your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs.
  * To send periodic emails — The email address you provide may be used to send you information, notifications that you request about changes to topics or in response to your user name, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.

## How do we protect your information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you enter, submit, or access your personal information.

## What is your data retention policy?

We will make a good faith effort to:

  * Retain server logs containing the IP address of all requests to this server no more than 90 days.
  * Retain the IP addresses associated with registered users and their posts no more than 5 years.

## Do we use cookies?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow). These cookies enable the site to recognize your browser and, if you have a registered account, associate it with your registered account.

We use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business.

## Do we disclose any information to outside parties?

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our site, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

## Third party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our site. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

## Children's Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

Our site, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older. If this server is in the USA, and you are under the age of 13, per the requirements of COPPA ([Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Children%27s_Online_Privacy_Protection_Act)), do not use this site.

## Online Privacy Policy Only

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our site and not to information collected offline.

MpSocial respects privacy rights under [Regulation (EU) 2016/679](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=uriserv:OJ.L_.2016.119.01.0001.01.ENG), the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Information that GDPR requires MpSocial to give can be found throughout this privacy notice.

## Where can I access data about me?

You can see your account data at any time by visiting your account page on the forum. Your account page also lists your posts and other activity on the forum.

Your account activity page also includes a link to download all of your activity in standard [comma-separated values](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comma-separated_values) format.

## How can I change or erase data about me?

You can change your account data at any time by visiting the profile settings page for your account. The settings of this forum may also allow you to close your account, on the settings page for your account. Closing your account starts a process of erasing or anonymizing MpSocial’s records of data you provided for your account. MpSocial can also erase and anonymize accounts.

Depending on the settings of this forum, you may also be able to edit, anonymize, or erase your posts. When you edit posts, MpSocial will keep all versions of your posts. Forum administrators can view old versions of posts, and optionally make them visible to other forum visitors.

## Does MpSocial make automated decisions based on data about me?

### MpSocial classifies posts as spam automatically.

MpSocial uses data about your posts and other activity to make automated decisions about whether your posts to [https://mpsocial.com](https://mpsocial.com/). When Akismet decides that a post is likely spam, the forum refuses to accept the post.

If you think a post has been wrongly blocked or removed, contact an administrator of your forum. They can override the decision that a post was spam.

### MpSocial uses data about posts and activity to set trust levels automatically.

MpSocial uses data about your posts and activity to award you badges and calculate a trust level for your account. Your trust level may affect how you can participate in the forum, such as whether you can upload images, as well as give you access to moderation and management powers in the forum. Your trust level therefore reflects forum administrators’ confidence in you, and their willingness to delegate community management functions, like moderation.

If you think your trust level has been set incorrectly, contact an administrator of your forum. They can manually adjust the trust level of your account.

## Does MpSocial share data about me with others?

MpSocial shares account data with others as mentioned in the section about account data.

MpSocial shares data about your posts and other forum activity with others as mentioned in the section about account data.

MpSocial does not sell or give information about you to other companies or services.

Other individuals and companies may also reuse data about you that MpSocial publishes, such as your posts to public forums.

You can send questions and complaints to:

MpSocial  

European Users with questions or complaints about GDPR compliance should also address MpSocial’s representative in the Union:

_Johnny_  
MpSocial  

For complaints under GDPR more generally, European Union users may lodge complaints with their local data protection supervisory authorities.

## How can I find out about changes?

This version of MpSocial’s privacy questions and answers took effect May 25, 2018.

MpSocial will post the next version at <https://mpsocial.com/privacy>. MpSocial may change how it announces changes in future versions.

In the meantime, MpSocial may update its contact information without announcing a change. Please refer to <https://mpsocial.com/privacy> for the latest contact information at any time.

## Your Consent

By using our site, you consent to our web site privacy policy.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page.

This document is Copyrighted. It was last updated May 25, 2018.
